請勿在家嘗試本片中的任何實驗
Don't try anything you see on this show at home.
我們進行的實驗非常危險
The things we do on this show are dangerous.
我們有專家協助保證我們的安全
We have experts to help keep us safe.
不太久以前
在一間不太遙遠的工作室里
《流言終結者》星球大戰特輯
這是一場與邪惡力量的爭戰
叛逆的科學家們在位于舊金山的秘密基地發起進攻  贏得了他們的第一場勝利
為了檢驗三個《星球大戰》流言  還原銀河系的真相
索菲亞·布什扮演莉婭公主
Sophia Bush is Princess Leia.
我們想知道能否用爪鉤
We want to know if you can make that swing
完成那次飛躍
using a grappling hook.
我們將用原木撞碎一輛裝甲車
It's about a log crushing an armored vehicle.
使用原力
Use the force.
完美
Perfect.
要把盧克放進湯湯里了
Luke is going into the Tauntaun.
我原以為它們只是外面難聞
And I thought they smelled bad on the outside.
這里是《流言終結者》星球大戰特輯
It's the "MythBusters" "Star Wars" Special.
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：瀟湘月影  cindysheva
流言終結者是何方神圣
Who are the MythBusters?
亞當·沙維奇
Adam Savage.
翻譯：橫排混血   衛管小色盲  兮之
我是你父親
I am your Father.
杰米·海曼
And Jamie Hyneman.
我挺喜歡這兒  有種私密感
I like it in here. It's private.
翻譯：欠斤夕四  foolyangyang  Foxer
他們有超過三十年的特技經驗
Between them, more than 30 years of special effects experience.
軸軸：雪貴人  小獄
與他們二位一道的是卡莉·拜倫
Together, with Kari Byron.
校對：Wei2321L  瀟湘月影  萌Su
救命  奧比旺·克諾比
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
托里·貝魯奇
Tory Belleci.
絕不
Never.
后期：8T
格蘭特·今原
And Grant Imahara.
我們可以一起統治宇宙
We could rule the universe together.
他們不光敘述流言
They don't just tell the myths.
他們還將流言付諸實踐
They put them to the test.
流言終結者
星球大戰特輯
我真不明白你為什么迷這些東西
I really don't get why you're into these things.
-迷哪些東西  -戲服
- Into what things? - Costumes.
我很高興你試圖理解我
I appreciate you trying to understand.
但你真的看過《星球大戰》嗎
But have you even seen "Star Wars"?
可能吧
Probably.
-咱們還是開始吧  -好啊
- Should we just get started? - Sure.
好的  在《星球大戰》里
Okay, in "Star Wars,"
盧克·天行者和莉婭公主
Luke Skywalker and Princess Leia are
想要逃離死星
trying to escape The Death Star.
他們要逃出帝國突擊隊的包圍
They are running from Stormtroopers
當跑到一扇關閉的門后
and they get behind a closed door
他們發現逃生之路
only to find their path blocked
被一道無法逾越的深淵擋住了
by a chasm they cannot cross.
快點  我們必須越過去
Quick! We've got to get across.
盧克從腰帶間抽出一只爪鉤
Luke pulls a grappling hook from his belt,
把它擲出去鉤住一塊死星上的硬物
swings it across some piece of Death Star hardware,
一手抱起莉婭
grabs Leia in his arm...
祝你好運
For Luck!
蕩到對面  重獲新生
and swings to safety.
我們想知道
So we want to know
是否能一手抱著你心愛的妹妹
if you could make that swing using a cable and a grappling hook
同時一手用纜繩和爪鉤成功蕩過鴻溝
while holding on to your sister who you have the hots for.
是可以這么說  沒錯
That is one way of looking at it, yes.
前方劇透
Spoiler alert!
身后有一個營的帝國突擊隊緊追不舍
So, with a battalion of Stormtroopers in hot pursuit,
盧克希望渺茫的飛躍真能成功嗎
can Luke's unlikely leap really be done?
作為一名帝國突擊隊員  你是不是矮了點
Aren't you a little short for a Stormtrooper?
你這么說很有趣
It's actually funny that you say that,
因為實際上
because in point of fact,
帝國突擊隊
種族  人類
身高  168cm
亞當·沙維奇  180cm
武器  爆能槍
所屬              銀河帝國
我比帝國突擊隊員要高一點
I'm a little tall to be a Stormtrooper.
管他的
Yeah, whatever.
趕緊開始吧
Let's shoot this pig.
別急  海曼
Not so fast, Hyneman.
有了帝國突擊隊制服和各種道具
I know with a Stormtrooper costume and all,
似乎我們已經準備好
it looks like we are ready to
全身心投入到《星球大戰》的世界中去
dive whole hog into the Star Wars universe.
但等一下  稍安勿躁
But wait, hold your horses,
在我們開始之前
because there is a whole bunch of set up to tell you about
還有一大堆設定要告知各位
before we even get to this point.
今天我們請來的超棒的帝國突擊隊員們
Our awesome group of Stormtroopers today
來自501軍團
comes courtesy of the 501st Legion,
那是一個由成千上萬星戰迷和角色扮演愛好者
an international group of thousands of
組成的國際性組織  他們喜歡做兩件事
"Star Wars" fans and cosplayers who like two things--
打扮成壞人  以及為慈善籌款
dressing up as the bad guys and raising money for charity.
我本人是組織的榮譽會員
I, myself, am an honorary member.
亞當·沙維奇
榮譽會員
再來看看這些服裝
Now here is to think about these customes.
服裝必須和電影里的一模一樣
Your costume has to be perfectly movie accurate.
我可以向你保證  我身后的每個人
I can guarantee you that everybody behind me has spend
都花了大量時間完善他們的服裝
hundreds of hours making their costumes perfect.
對嗎
Didn't you?
沒錯
Exactly.
在我們策劃這期節目時
Now we run into a unique problem
遇到一個特殊的問題
when we were planning out for this episode,
加州所有的死星場地都被租出去了
which is all of the death stars in California are being hired
我們一個都用不了
and we couldn't use any of them.
退而求其次  我們來到這里
So, second best was to come here,
一間始建于上世紀
to this beautiful previous century
位于北加州馬雷島的華麗補給倉庫
supply warehouse on Mare Island up in Northern California.
這里是我們最喜歡的地點之一
This is one of our favorite locations
我們曾在此拍攝過一些精彩的故事
and we've shot a few great stories here.
僵尸特輯S12E11
生死決斗S10E11
這里有點像1860版的死星
It's kind of like Death Star 1860.
你不覺得嗎
Don't you think?
相當漂亮
It's beautiful.
值得一提的是由特別嘉賓出演的壓軸好戲
And when it comes to the spectacular special guest airing grand finale,
索菲亞·布什
扮演
莉婭公主
杰米·海曼
扮演
盧克·天行者
請期待通向自由的翻腸倒胃的一躍吧
it has the hype required for the stomach churning leap for freedom.
他們來了
They're coming.
我們得離開這兒
We gotta get out of here.
但首先  我們實驗行動計劃是怎樣的呢
But, first, what's the experimental plan of action?
在驗證盧克蕩過深淵的實驗中
Now, in examining Luke swinging across the chasm.
我和杰米把它細分為三個要素
Jamie and I have broken it down into three distinct elements,
每項都需要進行實驗
each of which that needs testing.
一是爪鉤的表現
Number one is the behavior of the grappling hook.
緊緊
鉤住
以盧克的方式是否能投中并固定爪鉤呢
二是他的腰帶
Second would be his belt.
萬用
腰帶
腰帶能承受擺蕩的重量嗎
當他在纜繩上擺蕩時  腰帶能否支撐得住他
Would that be sufficient to support him while swinging on the line?
三是帶上莉婭公主的負擔
And third is the addition of Princess Leia.
雙人飛天
你能帶著一個活人蕩過鴻溝嗎
盧克不是一個人蕩過去的
Luke doesn't swing along acoss the chasm.
他還帶了一個人
He's got a passenger.
第一個實驗需要用到爪鉤
Since the first test involves a grappling hook,
所以我得動手做一個
I'm gonna have to make one.
它將與電影中盧克使用的爪鉤一模一樣
And it's gonna have to be identical to what Luke used in the movie.
完成了
And there we go.
真不錯
Sweet.
有了精巧的爪鉤
And with accurate grappling hook in hand...
這東西太棒了  伙計
That is gorgeous, dude.
和電影里一模一樣
That looks exactly like the movie.
可以進行第一項實驗了
it's test one.
他們能否像盧克一樣輕松纏繞并鉤住目標呢
Can you hit the target and wrap and hook as easily as Luke?
緊緊
鉤住
以盧克的方式是否能投中并固定爪鉤呢
我們朝哪扔啊
What are we throwing it over?
有一個和死星上一樣的絕佳靶子
We got a nice target right from the Death Star for you
就在上面
right up there.
可真夠遠的
Wow, that is quite a ways away.
距離大約是9到10米
That thing is about 30, 35 feet away.
我得說
And I got to tell you
想要一次成功可沒那么容易
that's quite a shot to do in one go.
我能釋放原力嗎  還是要我用手做
Can I use the force or do you want me to do this manually?
隨你怎么來
Whatever works for you.
好吧
Okay.
完全不知道結果會怎樣
I have no idea where this is gonna go.
接住了嗎
Catch it?
謝謝
Thanks.
顯然這可不像年輕的天行者向我們
Clearly, it's not as simple as the young Skywalker
展示的這么簡單
would have us believe.
投擲的高度倒是差不多
The height was about sufficient.
從和電影一樣的距離和角度
From the same distance and angle as in the movie.
好吧
All right.
掛到那了
So, now it's up there.
杰米一次又一次地苦苦嘗試
Jamie's struggling to get close.
就是扔不到柱子上
Hitting everywhere but the mast.
顯然他需要接受尤達大師的全套訓練
It's clear he needs a whole Yoda practice.
很接近了
So close.
盧克是典型的動作片英雄
Now, Luke is clearly the quintessential action hero.
只用一次機會
in only needing one chance, one try
就讓鉤爪命中了目標
to get the grappling hook over the correct target.
差得遠呢
Not quite.
事實上  從現在的情況看
In reality, at this point,
如果杰米是盧克  那盧克和莉婭早就被帶上銬鐐
if Jamie was Luke, Luke and Leia would be clapped in irons
丟到位于死星深處的
somewhere in a trash disposal,
某個垃圾站里了吧
somewhere in the depths of the Death Star,
電影也就此完結撒花了
and the movie's over.
但不能就這么結束  他最終一定要成功
But it can't end there. He's got to eventually get it.
好了伙計  這次是為了公主
Okey man, this one is for the Princess.
太棒了
Yes!
他總算命中了目標
He finally made the throw.
但鉤爪能否同電影中一樣牢牢抓住呢
But will it grapple and catch like in the movie.
勾住了
That's a hook.
來擊個掌
Give me a high five.
他成功了  他成功了
He got it. He got it.
看那  快看那里
Look at that. Look at that.
我認為沒使用原力我們也表現得很好
I think we get full marks for not using the force,
因為顯然你沒用
'cause it's clear that you weren't.
緊緊
鉤住
以卢克的方式是否能投中并固定爪钩呢
有此可能
理論上可行但實際上希望渺茫  實話實說
Plausible but unlikely. Let's face it.
杰米有寬裕的時間
Jamie had all the time in the world
可以隨心所欲地做嘗試
and as many tries as he wanted.
外加沒有追兵朝他開槍
And he didn't have anyone shooting at him.
太棒了
Yes.
祝你好運
For luck.
他成功了
He got it!
接下來  我們要好好研究一下盧克的腰帶
Next step, we're gonna have a closer look at Luke's belt.
因為他在擺蕩時  爪鉤
Because that's what his grappling hook
應該是系在腰帶上的
appears to be attached to when he does his swing.
我知道如果是安全帶的話應該可以
Now, I know this would work with a harness,
但對一條腰帶來說需要承受的重量太大了
but that's an awful lot of weight to support on a belt.
我們得試試才知道
We're gonna have to try it out.
準備好了嗎  伍基人
Ready, Wookiee?
萬用
腰帶
腰帶能承受擺蕩的重量嗎
一條腰帶能支撐住自己和孿生妹妹
So can a waist belt really support you
讓兩人安然無恙地蕩過鴻溝嗎
and your twin without serious injury?
好的  再往這邊一點
Yeah. Little bit more this way.
為了回答這個問題  亞當將和毛野人
To find out, Adam and the walking carpet
一起還原電影中的真實場景
go to work matching the exact layout from the silver-screen scene.
9.15米
但當他看到這條寬達9.15米的鴻溝時
But when he gets a look at 30-foot wide chasm,
安全地帶
我們的山寨天行者退縮了
our stand-in Skywalker's worried.
危險地帶
你想讓我就靠這個從這里蕩到那嗎
So you want me to swing from here to there just using that?
我覺得不靠譜
I don't think so.
危險地帶
這樣才差不多
This is more like it.
小試一下先
Baby steps first.
杰米擔心靠腰承受這樣的重量
Jamie's concern supporting the weight at his waist
會造成重傷
will lead to serious injury.
所以我們決定采用緩沖墊
So, with crash pads
同時縮短擺蕩距離和離地高度
and a shorter swing distance closer to the ground,
這樣萬一有危險發生  他能立即著地
he can be lowered immediately if there is any danger.
危險地帶
一般來說  如果你要蹦極
Normally, if you knew that you were gonna take a fall
或用繩子擺蕩
or swing on a rope,
你必須穿著兜住胯部的安全帶
you'd wear a harness that is between the legs.
準備好上了嗎
You want to hop up?
如果我只穿著這個從高處跳下去
If I jump off a height on a rope on this thing,
我擔心會折斷幾根肋骨
I'd be worried about breaking some ribs.
往上提一點
Let's take it up.
我想我們得試試才知道答案
I guess we're gonna have to try it to find out.
杰米
Jamie,
顯然因為腰帶硌到肋骨而非常不適
is clearly uncomfortable with the belt bruising his ribs.
公主送到  你可以出發了
Princess delivery, here you go.
又加上了孿生妹妹的重量
And with the added weight of a twin,
他能成功嗎
will he even make it?
我覺得  要把她轉過來
So she just turn around, I think.
抱穩了
There you go.
天吶
Oh, God.
記住  帝國突擊隊還在朝你開槍呢
Remember, Stormtroopers are shooting at you.
準備好了嗎  妹子
You ready, girl?
你怎么樣  運動健將
How you doing, sport?
我還好
I'm all right.
不過真的很疼啊
But, man, that hurts.
短距離的擺蕩已經痛苦不堪
Over the short distance, it was agony.
要想蕩過足足9.15米的鴻溝
Over the full 30 feet,
一定會是人間慘劇
it would be excruciating,
但它確實可以實現
but it can be done.
所以單用腰帶的話
So when it comes to the belt,
我必須承認
I have to admit,
理論上可以承受蕩過9.15米鴻溝的重量
it might be a plausible way to survive a 30-foot chasm swing.
但它絕不是安全  或者說
But it ain't a safe way, ie,
毫發無傷的方式
injury free way,
尤其是你懷里還抱著公主這樣的貴客
especially when one is holding on to precious cargo like a Princess.
在勉強驗證過兩關之后
With two marginally plausible cause,
萬用
腰帶
腰帶能承受擺蕩的重量嗎
有此可能
這條流言將將成立
this myth is barely hanging on.
在真正擺蕩的時候  我們將會采用不同的方案
We're gonna need a different solution for the real swing.
流言的第三個問題是  帶著孿生妹妹
Can part three, the full swing with a real twin
雙人飛天
你能帶著一個活人蕩過鴻溝嗎
能否蕩過鴻溝  逃過達斯·摩爾的追擊呢
rescue the result from the Darth Maul of defeat.
追尋答案  也要安全第一
To find out, it's safety first.
在第三場也是最后一場實驗中
For this third and final test,
我將從那里蕩過9.15米的鴻溝到達這里
I'm gonna be swinging from 30 feet away over there to here.
當然這次
Of course this time around,
我會穿上合適的安全吊帶
I'm gonna be wearing a proper safety harness
但愿不會傷到我
which hopefully won't hurt me
我們在下面鋪了安全墊
and we put safety mats down
以防萬一
in case something goes horribly wrong.
但愿用不上
Hopefully not.
這才是真正的安全帶
Now, that is a harness.
腰帶已被證明能在緊要關頭發揮作用
The belt already proven to work in a pinch literally
但我們決定把它換成安全帶
has been put aside in favor of a harness
以便讓本領不及絕地武士的杰米
that will allow not-so-Jedi Jamie
毫無痛苦地完成最終實驗
to complete the final test pain-free.
你好啊  先生
Howdy, sir.
現在亞當和杰米需要的
All Adam and Jamie are missing
是個如假包換的莉婭公主
is a real, live Leia look alike.
親愛的亞當和杰米
Dear Adam and Jamie,
《流言終結者》是我的摯愛節目
one of the things I love the most in the world is "Mythbusters."
一直以來我有個夢想
It would be my dream come true
就是和你們終結一個"星球大戰"流言
if I could help you guys bust a "Star Wars" Myth.
愛你們  索菲亞
Love, Sophia.
那是什么
What was that?
那是介紹我們的女演員前的蹩腳過場
That was our awkward transition to introduce our actress,
索菲亞·布什
Sophia Bush.
《芝加哥警署》中的星級演員
Cue star of NBC's Chicago PD
兼流言終結者的骨灰粉  索菲亞·布什
and massive "Mythbusters" fan, Sophia Bush.
先生們  你們好
Hello, gentlemen.
杰米  我能做你的莉婭公主嗎
Jamie, can I be your Princess Leia?
哪的話
Aw, shucks.
杰米  我要說
Now Jamie, I do want to point out that
索菲亞來客串公主可是經過精心打扮的
Sophia came to play dressed the part and everything.
你難道不應該
Don't you think you might want to
穿上些得體的衣服嗎
put on something a little more appropriate?
好吧
Fine.
你看起來帥呆了
You look fantastic!
馬上登陸探索頻道官網
Watch with Jamie and Adam live right now
和亞當杰米進行直播互動
on Discovery.com/MBlive
添加#Sithbusters
Use #Sithbusters
他們也許會在屏幕下方回答你的提問
and they might answer your question on screen.
《流言終結者》星球大戰特輯
在一個不太遠的紅木林中
In a redwood forest not so far, far away,
輪到卡莉  格蘭特和托里大顯身手了
it's Kari, Grant and Tory's turn to get their nerd on.
本期是星球大戰特輯
Okay, guys, so this is the "Star Wars" special
而我們在一片樹林中
and we're in a forest.
猜猜我們在哪個場景
Guess where we are?
顯然我們是在恩多星上
So clearly we're on Endor.
那一定是有關伊渥克的流言
So we must be doing Ewok myths.
完全正確
That's exactly right.
我們的流言來自于《絕地歸來》
We're doing the scene from "Return of the Jedi,"
片中伊渥克襲擊了全地形偵察機
where the Ewoks attack the All Terrain Scout Transport
用兩根巨大的原木將其砸爛
and smash it with two giant logs.
我們要驗證單憑
We're basically gonna see how much damage
兩根原木撞擺的沖擊
we can do to an armored vehicle
究竟能對一輛裝甲車造成多大傷害
using nothing but giant swinging logs.
本質上  這是個關于力學的流言
Essentially, this is a physics myth about forces.
不用原力嗎
Not the Force?
不是的  格蘭特
No, Grant.
要用科學的力量  格蘭特
Use the science, Grant.
對耶  對耶
Yep, yep!
R2  開始播放
R2, roll the clip.
這是個虛構宇宙中的虛構戰斗場景
It's a fictional battle scene from a fictional universe,
盡管如此  這個題設仍然有意義
but the hypothesis still stands.
一個原始的原木撞擺裝置
Could a primitive log-swing weapon
能否摧毀一輛堅固的裝甲車呢
really take out an reinforced, armored vehicle.
是不是該進入角色呢
Should we be in character?
不對
Uh, no.
這下好多了  剛剛那版莉婭簡直胡鬧
Oh, it's much better. That was totally the wrong Leia.
這才是恩多上的莉婭
It's Endor Leia
我想這個流言需要兩樣東西
So, it occurs to me that we are gonna need two things for this-
全地形偵察機
又稱"雞行者"
一臺全地形偵察機和一個巨型原木撞擺裝置
an AT-ST and a giant swinging log rig.
這個實驗的設備搭建工程將會非常瘋狂
The builds for this experiment are going to be insane.
因為這個原木撞擺是在是太巨大了
That log crushing rig looks gigantic.
這可不是開玩笑  納夫牛牧民們
那些原木長達3米  直徑1.5米
聽起來不錯
All right, sounds good.
我們該開工了
Guess we better get started.
回到地球上
Back here on Earth,
-放那邊吧  -對
- Let's Put it over there.  -Yep.
他們開始建造流言史上最浩大的工程之一
the team prepares for one of the biggest builds it's ever attempted.
R2  你最喜歡的流言終結者是誰
Hey R2, who is your favorite Mythbuster?
哄我開心呢吧
You are just saying that.
他們要再現恩多星上的茂密樹林
They are recreating the massive forest of Endor,
歸我了
Mine.
以及伊渥克獨創的巨型原木撞擺
and the Ewoks' ingenious giant log swing.
也許你會問  為什么選這么偏僻的地方
Why this abandoned field, you ask?
為什么不選一個和恩多的森林衛星
Why not something looks more like the forest moon of Endor,
即伊渥克的棲息地更相似的場景呢
the natural habitat of the Ewoks?
我們還不清楚當原木
Well, we don't actually know
擊中目標時會發生什么
what's gonna happen when the logs hit their target.
所以我們需要一個安全區域  即開放空間
So, we need a safety perimeter, a large wide open space.
因此這里是個理想的場地
And that makes this the ideal location.
問題在于
The question is,
我們該如何把它們懸掛在半空中
how are we gonna suspend them in midair
從而可以拉開它們
so that we can actually pull them apart
并且撞擊偵察機
and let them crush our Walker?
我們需要自己栽樹
Well, we are gonna plant our own trees,
其實是電話線桿
or telephone poles, at least,
當然要借助現代化器械
with the help of industrial power solutions.
工人們將先鉆些孔
They're gonna auger some holes.
然后插入木樁  這樣能節省不少時間
We are gonna lower the pole into it and save a bunch of time.
我不管你劇本上是怎么寫的
You know what? I don't really care what your script says.
奴隸版莉婭是不會出場的
I don't think slave Leia was in the scene.
不行
No.
根據影片  終結者們推斷出
From the movie, the team has determined
雞行者高約6米
that the height of the Chicken Walker is 20 feet.
原木從45度角開始下擺
The log swings from 45 degrees
長3米  直徑1.5米的原木
and what the relative size of those logs are
其相對尺寸為何呢
at 10 feet long and 5 feet in diameter,
那就是
the answer is-
太瘋狂了
Woo that is insane!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
碩大
Big!
電影中  伊渥克使用的像是紅木
Now in the movie, it looks like the Ewoks use redwood.
但那不是在地球上
But, since it wasn't planet Earth,
很難說他們用的是什么木頭
you don't really know what kind of wood it was.
R2  盧克主人要不高興了
Oh R2, oh Master Luke is not going to be happy.
因此我們決定
So we decided here on Earth,
選用地球上能找到的最堅硬的木材
we wanted to go with the hardest wood we could find,
也就是桉樹
which happens to be Eucalyptus.
每根原木重達4.5噸
Weighing in at 10,000 pounds each,
工人們必須添加交叉支撐
the guys get busy cross-bracing
和固定纜索來支撐其重量
and cable-anchoring the structure to support them.
是45度嗎
That 45?
我看差不多
I think that's 45-ish.
完成之后  原木搖滾即將開始
With that done, it's time to log and roll.
托里和我要將原木就位
Tory and I are putting the logs into place.
怎樣才能用一個4噸級的鏟車
Now, how do you move a 10,000-pound log,
去移動一個重達4.5噸的原木呢
when your forklift only has a 9,000-pound capacity?
原木搖滾秀
Yee, haw, log rodeo.
小心
Carefully.
請讓路  各位
Out of my way, people.
下一步
Next step,
是把原木吊起的關鍵步驟
the mission critical operation of craning the logs into position.
這個步驟會有些棘手
Now, it's gonna be very tricky,
因為正如你所見
because as you can see,
整個結構有很多的支柱
the structure has a lot of bracing,
想要把原木放進去
and it's going to be difficult
其實很困難
to actually get the logs inside of it.
真恐怖
That is terrifying.
別忘了這玩意有4.5噸重
Now remember these things are 10,000 pounds,
在操作上容不得半點差錯
and there is not a lot of room for mistakes.
已經有很嚴重的變形了
That is a lot of stretch right there.
無論這4.5噸的龐然大物
I mean, if this 10,000 pounds goes crashing
撞向任何一邊
to one side or the other,
整個結構都可能垮掉
the whole thing could come down.
好  原木已吊起
Okay, well, it's holding the log up.
不錯
That's good.
第二輪開始...
Round two...
還算順利
Looking good.
第二根原木...
and trunk two...
怎么轉得這么厲害
Why is that spinning like that?
老天啊
Holy crap.
好了
All right.
在不安中...
is nervously...
繼續往上吊
Keep coming.
就位完畢
maneuvered into position.
盡管支架發出吱嘎的抗議聲...
And despite the structure protesting...
你聽到斷裂聲了嗎
Can you hear the cracking?
經過調整加固之后...
once raised and supported...
好了
Yeah,
它似乎還堅挺
it seems to be holding.
這真棒
That's pretty gorgeous.
好了  我們搞定了
Okay, we're good.
就以往的工作壓力而言
As far as stressful workdays go,
今天的壓力強度還可以接受
this is reasonably stressful.
如釋重負后是滿滿的期待
And with the relief comes the anticipation.
我越來越激動了
I'm getting excited.
太酷了
This is so cool.
問題是  這種裝置真的管用嗎
Now, the question is, will the rig actually rock?
為了找出真相  他們開始了首次
To find out, they are starting out
木樁砸車測試
with a test swing on a test vehicle.
我們只想確保樹干是對齊的
We just want to make sure that our logs are lined up,
確保裝置工作正常
that our rig is working,
當然  看砸車一定很歡樂
and it's gonna be a lot of fun to see this thing crush.
集中精神  盧克
Concentrate, Luke.
使用原力
Use the force.
一切準備就緒
Once all the pieces are in place,
托里對這非凡的成就有所領悟
their incredible achievement dawns on Tory.
瞧  這幅場景是多么的超現實
Look at this. I mean how surreal is this situation,
這個看上去更像是"火人節"的儀式裝置
I mean this looks more like a Burning Man installation,
火人節  美國為期八天的反傳統節日
而非流言終結者的實驗
than a Mythbuster’s experiment.
不可思議的是
But the crazy thing is,
我們正在模擬《星球大戰》中的場景
we are actually replicating a "Star Wars" scene.
電影中  伊渥克先后砍斷
So in the movie, the ewoks cut one log
兩條繩子釋放木樁
and then cut the other log.
現實世界中
Here in the real world,
我們將同時釋放兩塊木樁
we're gonna release both logs simultaneously.
這究竟有多大能量呢
Now, how much energy are we talking about here?
每根原木約重4.5噸
Well, each log weighs 10,000 pounds.
將它們拉至約45度傾角
We raise them up to approximately 45 degrees.
好了  卡莉  保持這個位置
Okay, Kari, hold there.
托里  你來往上吊
Tory, let's have you boom in.
粗略算一下
Back-of-the-envelope math says
木樁的能量將超過一百萬焦耳
that's upwards of a million joules.
約一百萬焦耳
支架現在發出很大的動靜
You know, the structure is making a lot of noise right now.
是啊  相當瘋狂
Yes, this is looking crazy.
天哪  剛才算的能量是每根木樁
And oh, yeah, that’s each log,
因此總共有兩百萬焦耳的能量
which means 2 million joules of energy
撞向那輛貨車
hitting that van.
約兩百萬焦耳
我不確定否能將它拉至45度傾角
I don't know if we're gonna be able to get it to 45 degrees.
我覺得支架快撐不住了
I don't think it's gonna hold.
我同意  看起來不妙
Yeah, I agree, this is not looking that good.
兩根原木傾角還未到45度
With neither log close to 45 degrees,
裝置卻瀕臨坍塌...
and the rig in real danger of collapse...
支架開始斷裂了
It's starting to crack.
小組決定釋放木樁  避免損傷
the team decide to cut their losses and let loose.
就在這里放吧
I say we call it right here.
好的  快離開這里
OK, getting out of here.
倒數三  二  一
In three, two, one.
杰米此時有些不自在...
Jamie has slipped into something a little more uncomfortable...
你看上去太棒了
You look fantastic.
祝你好運
For luck.
為探究《星球大戰》中的飛躍是否可行
to find out if the "Star Wars" swing is possible.
測試過可以弄傷肋骨的腰帶后
With the rib-breaking belt benched,
裝備換成了安全護具
in favor of a safety-first harness,
他能成功抱著索菲亞到達彼岸嗎
can he hang on to Sophia while crossing the chasm?
為了測試裝置  杰米先獨自飛蕩...
To check the rig, Jamie first flying solo...
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
然后為正式實驗做最后準備...
and then prepares himself for the real deal...
干得漂亮
Nicely done. Well done.
帶假人排練
with a dummy demo.
索菲亞  稍后你和我
Sophia, this is what it's gonna sort to be like,
差不多就是這樣的
when you're up here with me.
開始吧
So, here we go.
真的會像這樣嗎
It's going to be like that?
我好期待啊
Really excited.
不會的  你可以抓緊他
It won't be like that. You will be able to hold on.
-這邊請  -好的
- Over there. - Okay.
干得漂亮  杰米
Nice work, Jamie.
我相信杰米不會松開我的
I am confident that Jamie is not going to drop me.
所以我很期待這個實驗
So I'm excited just get up there and do it.
這種心態很好
That is exactly the right attitude.
我想你會玩得很開心
I think you're gonna have a lot of fun.
我也這樣認為
Me, too.
像這樣雙手環抱
Both arms around like that.
結果如何  就看這一躍了
And so, it comes down to this.
你怎么抓繩索呢
How are you holding the rope?
我用這只手抓繩索
I'm holding it with this hand.
之前的兩個步驟
With the first two pieces
有此可能
已被證明可行
of the puzzle already proven plausible.
有此可能
-冷靜點  -馬上就好
- Gotta calm down. - Coming in.
杰米熟練地系上繩索
Jamie's expertly strapped in
準備最后的測試
for the third and final test.
雙人飛天
The twin tow.
你能帶著一個活人蕩過鴻溝嗎
帝國突擊隊已就緒
Stormtroopers ready.
盧克和莉婭  就看你們的表現了
All right, Luke and Leia. It's up to you.
進入角色  創造奇跡吧
Get into character, make this happen.
各就各位
On your marks.
他們追過來了
They're coming.
我們得離開這里
We gotta get out of here.
危險區
安全區
你們真的做到了
You totally did it!
太棒了  干得漂亮
Excellent, well done!
來啊  你們這群帝國士兵
Bite me, Empire!
經過精心的分析和設計
After all this break down and all this planning,
實驗再順利不過了
that could not have gone better.
非常令人滿意
Very satisfying.
每一步都如同你想象中的那般有趣
Every bit as much fun as you think.
我們做的幾乎完美了
Well, we pretty much nailed that.
但我得說
But I got to say,
這個測試的多個部分都屬于擦邊球
most of the stuff we are testing here has been pretty borderline.
如果面臨生死關頭
If it's a life-and-death situation,
當然  你可以投擲爪鉤
sure, you can throw a grappling hook.
但真的能一次命中嗎
But are you gonna be able to get it in one go?
有此可能
沒錯  你確實可以將繩索系在腰帶上
And yes, you can swing on a cable by tying it onto your belt
有此可能
然后實現帶人飛躍
and carrying another person.
但在生死關頭呢
Life and death situation?
也許可以  但還是比較懸的
Sure, but it's all pretty dodgy, really.
伙計們  我們時間不多了
All right, dudes, we don't have much time,
帝國士兵追來了
'cause the Empire is coming.
這個流言怎么定論呢  索菲亞
How do you want to call this one? Sophia?
我們成功蕩到了對面
We made it a cross.
-我覺得有此可能  -杰米呢
- I say it's plausible. - Jamie
明顯這是可行的
Well, you know, it's clearly possible.
我真的很想說流言被證實了
But that makes me want to say it's confirmed.
有此可能
Plausible.
《流言終結者》下節預告
Coming up on "MythBusters,"
我們將驗證盧克能否靠待在湯湯體內
we find out if Luke really could have survived a night on Hoth
在霍斯星上存活一晚
inside a Tauntaun.
這里是《流言終結者》星球大戰特輯
It's a "Star Wars" MythBusters baby.
馬上登陸探索頻道官網
Watch with Jamie and Adam live right now
和亞當杰米進行直播互動
on discovery.com/mblive
添加#Sithbusters
Use #Sithbusters
他們也許會在屏幕下方回答你的提問
and they might answer your question on screen.
流言終結者
星球大戰特輯
準備好進行下一項實驗了嗎
You ready for the next one?
差不多吧
I guess.
這個流言來自《星球大戰》系列電影
The myth we’ve got comes from the "Star Wars" movie
《帝國反擊戰》
"The Empire Strikes Back."
盧克
Luke!
夜幕降臨冰雪覆蓋的霍斯星
Darkness is falling on the ice planet of Hoth.
堅持住  盧克
Don't do this, Luke.
漢騎著一種叫湯湯的動物來找盧克
Han has ridden a beast called a Tauntaun to find Luke.
他剖開了湯湯的肚皮
Han slices open the belly of Tauntaun
把盧克放了進去  說道...
and puts Luke inside and says...
味道可能不大好聞  小子...
This may smell bad, kid...
尤達
Yoda.
但能在我挖好雪洞之前保持你的體溫
But it will keep you warm till I get the shelter up.
我們要解答的問題是
The question for us to answer is,
漢是否為盧克選擇了正確的雪地求生方法
did Han make the right cold-weather survival call for Luke?
那我們就去霍斯檢驗一下吧
Great. Let's go to Hoth and test it.
好的
Cool.
我原以為它們只是外面難聞
I thought they smelled bad on the outside.
杰米說到了點子上
Jamie's got a point.
想在地球上驗證這條流言
To bring the myth back to Earth,
亞當和杰米得復制出霍斯惡劣的環境
Adam and Jamie will eventually replicate Hoth's inhospitable environment.
并找到一個安全的方法
and find a way to safely test human hypothermia
在動物內臟中進行人體低溫實驗
while neck deep in internal organs.
這是脾
Here comes the spleen.
但首先得做出一個湯湯來裝這些內臟
But the first task is to make a Tauntaun to house those guts.
在兩天的時間里
Embarking on a build like an 8-foot tall Tauntaun
單手建造一個2.4米高的湯湯
in two days with one hand
就像一個馬戲演員
is kind of like a circus performer
把腦袋伸進獅子的嘴里一樣
putting his head in the lion's mouth.
他還挺確定自己沒問題的
He is pretty sure it's gonna go okay.
運用網格法
From using the grid system
將湯湯的形象
to transfer the image of the Tauntaun
畫到這塊抬都抬不動不動的泡沫上
to this block of foam I couldn't even lift by myself.
與常規想法不同
The first cut,
初次切割不是切得最深的
contrary to popular belief is not the deepest.
在那塊泡沫上切割出
To the fact that just cutting up the basic shape of the Tauntaun
湯湯的大概形狀
in that block of foam,
用了兩個小時  讓我汗流浹背精疲力盡
took two hours and left me sweaty and spent and exhausted.
真是好大一塊泡沫啊
Get a big piece of foam, I said.
我要用它雕刻出一個湯湯呢
I'll carve a Tauntaun out of it, I said.
幸運的是  杰米給了我一些建議
Luckily, Jamie gave me advice about
亞當的玩笑話  節目組所在的舊金山
在19世紀70年代是美國太平洋沿岸最重要的捕鯨船港
他曾在19世紀70年代
when he used to slice whale blubber
從小須鯨身上切過鯨脂
off the minke whales in the 1870s.
好嘞
There we go.
當我終于拿出工具
Once I finally got my foam tool out
開始切割湯湯的輪廓
and started cutting the contours of the Tauntaun,
成型速度比我預想的要快得多
the shape came into being much faster than I expected.
對了  你可能想知道我為什么綁著夾板
Right, you've been wondering why I 'm wearing a splint,
是因為我在搬一件安全設備的時候
it's because I was moving a piece of safety equipment,
它砸到了我的手上
and it fell on my hand
把我的第二掌骨的頂部砸碎了
and crushed the top of my second metacarpal
真是諷刺
and ironic.
好了
All right.
我的湯湯已經雕刻好了
My Tauntaun is totally complete in terms of being sculpted,
但還得給它加上毛皮
but it needs an outer layer of skin and fur.
輪到它派上用場了
And that's where this comes in.
該給你加上毛皮了  老兄
Time to fur you up, dude.
我在做我12歲時
I'm making, literally, the stuffed animal
夢寐以求的毛絨玩具呢
I dreamed about when I was 12 years old.
乖寶寶
You're a good boy.
野獸是多么有趣的群體啊
Monsters are such interesting people.
好嘞
There we go.
它現在有爪子了
He's no longer armless.
與此同時  杰米正在給它做內臟
Meanwhile, Jamie is ensuring he's not gutless either.
湯湯是由各種各樣的東西組成的
Tauntauns are made up of all sorts of stuff,
但我們只關注腹腔
but we are interested in the gut cavity,
因為盧克要在那里過夜
because that's where Luke is gonna be spending the night.
所以我得做
So I've got to make
一大堆惡心的內臟器官
a whole bunch of disgusting organs and viscera.
就這樣
Yeah, baby.
使其能像在霍斯星一樣傳導熱量
And that will conduct heat the same way it would on the planet Hoth.
我們的瘋狂科學家杰米
Cue our resident mad scientist.
將塑料熔化后進行重塑
Using a melt-and-mold plastic,
以此尋找做假器官襯套的
Jamie searches for the perfect recipe
完美方法
for the perfect fake organ lining.
這就是湯湯的闌尾了
That right there is the Tauntaun appendix.
但要經過幾個小時的反復實驗
But it takes several hours of trial and error...
它在往下滴
Oh, it's dripping.
科學怪人海曼...
before Dr. Franken-Hyneman...
真好玩
We have such fun.
才能找到正確的配方和制作方法
hits on the right formula and manufacturing technique.
這才是我想要的
That's what I'm talking about.
只有經過這樣的實驗
This kind of experimentation
你才能取得這樣的成果
is pretty much the only way you get to this sort of result.
湯湯的內臟
Tauntaun guts.
再給它們灌滿黏糊糊的東西
When we fill this with some kind of goopy stuff,
看起來就像真器官了
it's gonna look totally organic.
不僅長得像
It's not just the looks.
把它們填滿并加熱后放進湯湯的腹腔
When filled, warmed and placed in the body cavity.
杰米做的這些腸子就會有
Jamie's Tauntaun intestines will have the same
與內臟器官一樣的導熱性能了
thermal conductive properties of internal organs.
我得承認  我13歲的時候
I have to admit that when I was 13
很向往星戰中的世界
and I fantasized about being inside the Star Wars' universe,
但是我從來沒想到
I have to tell you, it never occurred to me
有一天我會給一只湯湯做手術
that I would be operating on a Tauntaun.
腹腔做得就像一個漂亮整潔的信封
The cavity is set up like a nice, neat envelope.
現在我們只需要盧克·天行者的替身
And all we need now is a stand-in Luke Skywalker.
最好是那種能被凍死的
Hopefully, one that can freeze to death.
我想想  有了
Let's see. Ding! Found it.
還記得這個
Remember this guy
在"泰坦尼克的故事"中用到的假人么
we built for the "Titanic" myth?
看看你  小帥哥
Look at you, you handsome devil.
他全身有四百米長的銅制血管
He's got over a quarter mile of copper-tubing veins,
和一個三百瓦的加熱器
plus a 300-watt heater
心臟
能讓他的體溫一直保持在37攝氏度
that keeps his body temperature at exactly 98.6.
我們只需給他穿上盧克的衣服
All we've got to do is dress him up in Luke's costume,
把他放進湯湯的肚子  再把湯湯放進冷庫
stuff him in our finished Tauntaun inside some kind of freezer
不過冷庫還沒想好怎么做
we haven't figured out how to build yet
然后就來驗證這條流言
and we get to test this myth.
上啊  上啊
Go, go.
我第一次看《星球大戰》的時候還是個孩子
Now, I remember the first time I saw Star Wars as a little kid.
那部電影徹底改變了我的人生
And the moment I saw that movie my whole life was changed.
1977年《星球大戰》上映時我七歲
I was 7 years old when Star Wars came out in 1977.
我跟媽媽一起在好萊塢中國劇院外面排隊等候
I waited in line outside the Mann's Chinese theatre in Hollywood with my mom.
長大后  我甚至在跟亞當和托里一起
And I even grew up to work on the Star Wars series as an adult
在工業光魔公司的模型車間里
at Industrial Light and Magic in the model shop
為星戰系列效力
along with Adam and Tory.
這就像是夢想成真了
I mean it was like a dream come true.
現在我們在《流言終結者》里
And now to be here on MythBusters,
檢驗星戰電影中的流言  太讓人興奮了
testing myths from the movie, it's like, blows my mind.
這是我自己的漢·索羅服
This is my personal Han Solo costume.
沒錯  我就是個鐵粉
So, yeah, you can say I'm a fan.
要是有一把真正的光劍就更好了
The only thing can be better is having a real light saber.
與此同時  在另一邊的實驗場地上...
Meanwhile, back at the trial run...
好的  就到這里
Okay, stop there.
好  趕快離開
OK, get out of here.
雞行者粉碎機在拉力作用下嘎嘎作響
The Chicken Walker crusher is cracking under the strain.
離45度角還有些距離
Some way short of the full 45 degrees.
如果現在不松開  支架可能就要塌了
It's let loose now or risk a catastrophic collapse.
好的  這里是巨木粉碎機的概念驗證
All right, this is giant log crusher, proof of concept.
放吧  格蘭特
Take it away, Grant.
三  二  一
In three, two, one.
雖然還未達到理想的釋放高度
They may not have reached the ideal swing height,
但是現在的破壞力已經足夠驚人了
but there was an encouraging amount of destruction.
真是太棒了
That was awesome.
我覺得這可以算成功
I would call that a success.
伊渥克人的武器看起來能行
The Ewok weapon seemed to work.
但是  若換做是一輛裝甲車...
However, I think if we put the armored vehicle up there...
伊渥克人會被這車碾碎的
Ewoks are squishy when you run them over.
就不會產生和剛才一樣的損害了
we are not going to see the same type of damage.
這家伙看起來堅不可摧
This thing feels indestructible.
這輛又大又結實的卡車
This big, badass truck right here
就是我們《流言終結者》找到的
is our Mythbusters' answer to the light armored vehicle
在伊渥克的叢林里巡邏的輕型裝甲車
that scout through the Ewok forest.
看起來好多了
That's better.
我真的很好奇伊渥克人能否干掉它
I'm really curious to see if the Ewoks could take this down.
要想找到答案  他們必須重整裝備
To find out, they need to seriously reconfigure the rig.
首先要做的就是
And the first part of the solution
用鋼筋來加固
is more steel for more strength.
然后再來說裝甲車
Now we are moving on to the armored vehicle.
我們將把它放在地上
We are gonna place that on the ground
并把巨木降到同樣的高度
and lower the logs to the same level.
這樣做的好處是
What that's gonna do...
纜繩長度會變長
it's gonna give us more length on the cable
也就是說我們可以把巨木拉得更高
which in turn means we will be able to lift those logs higher
所以當我們釋放它們時
and so, when we release them,
就會產生大得多的能量
it's gonna give us a lot more energy.
和這輛裝甲車說再見吧
Say good-bye to the armored truck.
加長的纜繩可以保證
The lengthened cable should ensure
巨木達到要求的45度
they get to the requisite 45 degrees.
但由于無法估測結構的穩定性
But with structural stability far from certain,
大家都撤離到了安全地帶
the guys retreat to safety.
好了  伙計們  把巨木拉起來吧
OK, guys, go ahead and pull the logs up.
隨著巨木將被拉到預定位置
And while the logs are winched into position,
格蘭特將會回答你們亟待解決的問題
Grant will answer your burning question.
你們也許會說  等一下
OK, so you are saying, "Now, wait a minute,
裝甲車與全地形偵察機所處的高度不同啊
your vehicle is not at the same height as the AT-ST."
是的  但是回憶下這條流言的內容
Well, just remember what this myth is about.
流言說的是兩段巨木能否摧毀一輛裝甲車
It's about two giant logs crushing an armored vehicle.
所以是在空中還是在地上并不重要
And that can happen whether it's in the air or on the ground.
盡管受到巨大力量的拉扯
Despite the incredible forces at play,
裝置依舊穩固
the swing is holding,
隨著巨木到達預計位置...
and with the logs in their start position...
好的  放吧
All right, take it away.
是時候驗證伊渥克人的擺動打擊的法子
it's time to find out if the Ewoks' rope-and-stick trick
是否真能摧毀
could have really crushed
邪惡帝國的鋼鐵機械
the steely mechanical might of the evil empire.
這次是巨木粉碎機對雞行者
This is log crusher against Chicken Walker,
實際是輛裝甲車
actually armored truck
三  二  一
in three, two, one.
實在是太酷了
That was so cool.
真是太漂亮了
That was beautiful.
這就是答案
There is your answer.
提問
Ask...
星球大戰
Star Wars.
和回答
and answer.
我們肯定讓那些伊渥克人非常驕傲
I really think we're making all those little Ewoks proud.
我們驗證的不是他們能否造出這樣的武器
We are not testing whether or not Ewoks could build this weapon.
我們假設他們可以
We are assuming they could.
我們驗證的是
But what we're testing is
它是否是一種有效的武器
whether or not it's an effective weapon.
而我們證明了它是的
And we have proved that it is.
然而  你得是個特別幸運的小伊渥克人
However, you'd had to be the luckiest little Ewok
能夠保證某個雞行者的
to make sure that one of those Chicken Walkers
高度正好合適
was at the right height
并在巨木撞擊時又出現在恰當的位置
and it was at the right spot when the two logs came together.
在我看來  可能性真是微乎其微
To me, that is a one-in-a-million shot.
雖然可能性很小  但還是可能的
Unlikely, but possible.
本條流言有此可能
The myth is plausible.
但是事情還沒完
But they are not done yet.
現在我們免費贈送一次撞擊
Now we are just looking for some gratuitous crashing and smashing.
我們將在車里安置一名帝國突擊隊員
So we are gonna add a stormtrooper to the cab...
別擔心那些伊渥克人
Don't worry about those Ewoks.
你在一輛裝甲車里
You're in an armored vehicle.
沒什么可擔心的
You got nothing to worry about.
把車放回去  用我們的武器狠狠地撞它
Push it back, smash it with our log crusher.
為什么  就是為了爽
Why? Just for the hell of it.
開火
Fire.
這下可要頭疼了
Oh, that's gonna be a headache.
今天一定是恩多星上反叛軍的好日子
Well, I guess it's a good day for the rebels on Endor.
回家吧
Let's go home.
有此可能
流言終結者
星球大戰特輯
要知道在我小時候
You know, there wasn't a lot of
除了莉婭公主
really great female Sci-Fi characters
還真沒有什么偉大的女性科幻角色
when I was growing up except Princess Leia.
她不僅是一名公主  還是一名戰士
Not only was she a Princes, but she was also a warrior.
我很喜歡這一點
I really like that.
我一直喜歡的是波巴·費特
My all time favorite is Boba Fett.
因為他很神秘  他是匹獨狼
Because he's mysterious. He works alone.
他邪惡無比  而且總能達到目的
He's a bad mother and he always gets his target.
這點和我很像
I can relate to that.
記著孩子們  霍斯可不是個旅游圣地
Remember, kids, Hoth is not a tourist destination.
這是一顆危險的冰雪星球
It is a hostile ice planet.
請勿在家嘗試本片中的任何實驗
Don't try anything you are about to see at home.
我們就是你們所稱的專家
No, we're what you call experts.
《流言終結者》星球大戰特輯
亞當和杰米正在測試湯湯睡袋
Adam and Jamie are testing the Tauntaun sleeping bag.
他們有了一只湯湯  有了它的內臟
They have a Tauntaun, the intestines,
還復活了接受低溫測試的熱力俠
and they resurrected hypothermia testee thermo-boy.
瞧瞧你  小帥哥
Look at you, you handsome devil.
現在他們正前往霍斯
Now they head for Hoth.
保持冷藏或冷凍
無骨去皮雞腿肉
含至多達5%的多磷酸鈉水溶液
注意
小心地滑
歡迎來到冰雪星球霍斯
Welcome to the ice planet of Hoth.
好吧  這里不是霍斯
Okay, it's not Hoth.
這是一個食物冷藏庫
It's a refrigerator storage facility for food.
但這里剛好可以用來模擬霍斯的環境
But it's perfect for us to recreate the conditions on Hoth.
這樣便宜得多
This is low budget.
只需要點布景就行
All we need is a little set dressing.
為了達到遠低于冰點的溫度
And temperatures way, way below freezing,
他們在本就寒冷不已的冷庫內
and for that, they are building a dry ice box
建造了一個干冰箱
inside the already icy facility.
真是個大家伙
He's a big beast.
我正站在一個十厘米厚的隔熱泡沫板上
I'm standing on a four-inch thick slab of insulating foam.
我們會像鋪路一樣
On top of this, we are gonna place
在它上面放置干冰塊
like paving stones, bricks of dry ice
然后把湯湯放在上面
and then the Tauntaun goes on top of that.
為了保持低溫效果
Now in order to hold that cold in,
在實驗期間  我們會把
we're going box the Tauntaun in
湯湯給封起來
for the duration of the experiment.
我覺得這個方法完全可行
I think that worked out, actually, quite nicely.
箱子會蓋住它并保留住冷氣
That box is gonna cover over him and hold that cold,
而泡沫地板也會防止冷氣流失
and this foam floor will keep that cold from getting away.
干冰有個好處
Great thing about dry ice is
當你在冬衣里覺得熱了
if you feel a little overly warm,
你可以往里面放一塊
in your winter suit, just put one of these inside.
調節一下你的溫度
Regulate your own temp.
好吧  這是個笑話
Okay, that was a joke.
我是開玩笑的
I was kidding.
顯然  想讓冷庫里足夠冷
So clearly we are going to a lot of trouble
我們還有很多工作要做
to make it quite cold in our freezer.
但是到底要多冷呢
But what's our goal?
霍斯上的溫度是多少
What is the temperature on Hoth?
電影中沒人說過溫度到底是多少
No one in the movie states the actual temperature.
所以我們查了一下伍基百科
So we looked it up on Wookieepedia.
伍基百科說霍斯上的溫度
And Wookieepedia told us that the temperature on Hoth
介于零下30至零下60攝氏度之間
is between negative 30 and negative 60 degree celsius.
霍斯
地區  外層空間
直徑  7200公里
氣溫  -32℃~-61℃
但這個數據來自于《星球大戰》放映十年后
But that figure comes from a role-playing game
發布的一款角色扮演游戲
released 10 years after the Star Wars films.
看起來有點不靠譜
Seems a little arbitrary.
但鑒于我們的目的是
But for our purposes,
延續星戰世界的經典
to remain canon with the Star Wars universe
只要冷庫能達到零下30度到零下60度
as long as our freezer gets between negative 30 and negative 60,
我們就滿足了
we're happy
我們也會覺得很冷
and we will be cold.
那是外部環境
That is the outside environment.
現在輪到體內的內臟了
Now for the inside of the insides.
湯湯似乎把我身上都染藍了
It looks like Tauntaun got blue to me.
被染成藍色以后
When dyed blue,
用來填充湯湯腸子的聚丙烯酸鈉...
sodium polyacrylate is a suitably gross filling...
我也有過這樣的早晨
I've had mornings like this.
變得非常惡心
for the Tauntaun intestines.
這個泵很不錯
Oh the pump's working great.
我們可以用這個方法填充內臟
I think this is our method for filling our guts.
很棒  也很惡心
Brilliant, and disgusting.
你弄得腳上都是
You got it all over your feet.
填充好后...
Once filled...
看來它需要補充點纖維素
It looks like he needs a little more fiber.
將它們泡在浴缸里加熱到37攝氏度
they'll be warmed in a bath to 99 degrees fahrenheit.
一只剛死去的北極動物就是這個溫度
The body temperature of a recently dead Arctic animal.
我要把它綁到管子上面
I'm just gonna zip tie this to this
然后一邊填充一邊給腸子按摩
and then massage the guts through the intestines as we go.
太棒了
That's just fantastic.
你是說我會制造內臟還是什么
Can I make guts or what?
這玩意總是對著我放屁
This thing keeps farting on me.
湯湯腸子實驗室
Tauntaun bowel labs.
滿滿的都是腸子和樂子
It's all fun and guts...
太棒了
Perfect.
直到有人弄破了一個腸子
until someone perforates a bowel.
昨晚  我們把一切都準備好了
Well, we had everything set and beautiful last night
制造湯湯的第二天
就等內臟今早成型了  但是有一個問題
with the guts coming this morning and there is a problem.
問題出在我們昨天用來
The problem is that the zip ties
給腸子封口的扎線帶上
we used to close up the ends of all of our guts
它們穿透了乙烯基塑料
ended up working their way
把它撕裂了
through the vinyl and tearing it.
所以每根腸子都漏了
So every single one of our guts is evacuating itself.
太糟糕了
That one's really bad.
所以我現在打算把它們全部清空
So I'm now attempting to empty them all out,
再混點別的東西進去
mix up a bunch more stuff to go in this
然后在短時間內重新做一些
and remake them in a very, very short period of time.
現在是關鍵時刻
It's now of the essence.
由于之前的失敗  現在必須趕緊準備好
With the setback, it's now a race to get set up.
首先進入浴缸的是熱力俠
First into the bath is thermo-boy
因為他得在實驗開始前
since he needs to reach body temperature
加熱到人體溫度
before the experiment can begin.
很好
Excellent.
這就像是舒服的熱水浴一樣
The water is like a nice, really hot bath.
但內臟卻問題不斷
But there is no end to the guts problem.
它們都沒封口
There's no ends on any of these.
這是一個
This is one.
這些重新扎好的管子不知怎么的又散了
The retied tubes have somehow untied themselves.
溫度導致了變化
The heat is changing things.
真奇怪  這些東西看起來很有彈性
It's just bizarre. This stuff seemed so resilient
可一旦把它放到水里  它就四分五裂了
and when you put it in water and it's like, falling to pieces.
這真是一個非常令人沮喪的早晨
This has been a very frustrating morning,
沒有身處霍斯那么沮喪  但也差不多了
not as frustrating as being on Hoth. But very.
杰米不屈不撓地又將這些內臟綁好
Undeterred, Jamie laboriously reties the organs
亞當則給熱力俠準備好心臟泵和加熱器
while Adam plumps in thermo-boy's heart pump and heater.
溫度達到37攝氏度  我們就開始測試
When this gets to 99, we are ready to start this test.
當腸子的溫度達到人體溫度  情況開始好轉
And as they approach body temperature, things are looking up.
這個心臟泵是我喜歡的實驗部分
This heart here is one of my favourite parts of this experiment.
除了安裝在假人體內  湯湯體內
In addition to temperature sensors in his body, in the Taunaun
和環境中的溫度傳感器外
and in the atmosphere over there,
這個心臟泵能為他全身供血
this heart will be pumping blood through him.
供血量和人體新陳代謝一致
And it's been calibrated to have the same metabolism as a human body.
所以如果他無法承受寒冷  開始出問題時
So if he can't keep up in the cold and starts to go sour
我們就能從這個溫度表上看出來
we will see it right here on this temperature gauge.
但是當熱力俠穿好衣服后
But as thermo-boy gets in the costume,
還有一個災難在等著這個多災多難的實驗
this cursed experiment has more heartbreak in store.
把泵關掉
Turn the pump off.
一個銅管動脈破裂了
A copper tube artery has burst.
他在流血呢
He's bleeding.
如果他在凍死前就因失血過多而死
If he bleeds to death before he freezes to death,
這個實驗就無效了
it's not a valid experiment.
你要噴燈嗎
Do you want a blowtorch?
咱們把他滾過去
Let's roll him.
海曼醫生開始工作了
Dr.Hyneman goes to work.
我們能放點什么在他齒間讓他咬著嗎
Can we get something to put between his teeth to bite down on?
由于沒有保險...
With no insurance to speak of...
請把鑷子遞給我
Nippers, please.
盧克只得到了最基本的護理
Luke gets a fairly basic level of care.
刀  誰有刀
A knife, anybody with a knife.
熱力俠在泰坦尼克那集表現得非常好
Thermo-boy here was a champ on the "Titanic" episode
我造它的時候就修補過
but I sort of was making it up as I went when I built him
它也很爭氣
and he is pretty ambitious.
但循環系統泄漏了
But we sprung a leak in circulatory system
事情就是這樣
and that is all she wrote.
別擔心  熱力俠
Don't worry, thermo-boy,
我們馬上就能讓你恢復如初
we will have you good as new in a minute.
我們無法讓它進行新陳代謝
Because we can't provide him with his metabolism,
就無法監控它的溫度
we can't monitor his temperature,
除非它的循環系統能正常工作
we don't have a valid test
否則我們無法有效地進行實驗
unless his circulatory system is working.
這是血  沒有漏出來
It's blood, and no leaks.
在浪費了一整天后
Well our day of "two steps forward and one step back"
我們"走兩步退一步"的一天終于結束了
has culminated in effectively what is a waste of a whole day.
有趣的是
You know it's funny,
出于某種原因  只要我開始工作
for some reason any time I do a job,
就會有東西著火
things start to burn.
希望我們能吸取今天的教訓
Hopefully, we've learned from our mistakes,
明天進行得更順利一些
so it'll go much smoother tomorrow.
希望永無止息
Hope springs eternal.
馬上登陸探索頻道官網
Watch with Jamie and Adam live right now
和亞當杰米進行直播互動
on Discovery.com/MBlive.
添加#Sithbusters
Use #Sithbusters
他們或許會在屏幕下方回答你的問題
and they might answer your question on screen.
修補好熱力俠...
With thermo-boy patched up...
制造湯湯的第三天
第二條褲子穿好了
The second pair of pants on.
并給它穿好衣服  昨天的麻煩...
and dressed up, the troubles of yesterday...
湯湯到了  誰訂的湯湯
Tauntaun delivery. Who ordered the Tauntaun?
似乎是很久前的事情了
seem so far away.
下一步就是將盧克放到湯湯里
So now the next step is to put Luke in a Tauntaun.
聽起來真不錯
It sounds perfect.
將他置于霍斯零下的溫度之中
Put him in the sub zero weather of Hoth
讓我們看看漢的決定是否正確
and find out if Han was doing the right thing.
盧克就位以后
Once Luke is in place,
他們會將努力搶救而來的器官放進去
they'll add the organs they managed to salvage.
同時  倒入加熱過的體液
Meanwhile, in go the bath-warmed bodily fluids...
一大堆滑膩膩臟兮兮的湯湯內臟
Great big gops of goopy, grimy Tauntaun guts.
這讓人不禁疑惑
which raises a question
湯湯到底是什么
what is a Tauntaun anyway?
好的  抬起來
Okay, up.
有一個虛構的生物叫做湯湯
Ok, so we got this fictitious creature named a Tauntaun
它來自一個叫做霍斯的虛構的星球
and it comes from the fictitious planet Hoth
這個星球非常的寒冷
which we know is very cold.
盧克就要躺進湯湯身體里了
Luke is going into the Tauntaun.
大小還挺合適
That actually fit.
我們按照北極熊的樣子
We've decided to construct our Tauntaun
設計出了湯湯
to be very like a Polar bear.
我還以為它們只是外面難聞
And I thought they smelled bad on the outside.
北極熊有一層很厚的皮毛
A Polar bear has a thick layer of fur
和一層很厚的脂肪
and a thick layer of blubber.
這是肝  下一個是脾
That's the liver. Here comes spleen.
我們的湯湯有一層很厚的皮毛
Our Tauntaun has a thick layer of fur
但里面不是脂肪  而是泡沫橡膠
but in lieu of blubber, it has some foam rubber.
我知道那是什么
I know what that is.
為了保持一致
To maintain that model,
測試開始前我們將湯湯的核心溫度調至
the Tauntaun's core temperature will start the test
與北極熊一樣的37攝氏度
about the same as a polar bear's, 99 degrees fahrenheit.
湯湯快遞
Tauntaun express.
你左邊有地方嗎
You clear on your left?
好了  你可以把它放下來了
All right, you can low him down.
但這并不容易
But it's far from easy.
必須把湯湯的核心溫度
With necessity to have the Tauntaun's core temperature
設置為正確的數值
be the right number
盧克的核心溫度設置在正確的數值
and Luke's core temperature being the right number...
好了  我要啟動盧克的心臟了
All right, I'm gonna start Luke's heart.
霍斯星球的實際表面溫度也要設置正確
and the actual Hoth planet surface being the right temperature,
四周還要搭建遮蓋物  里面放入探針
the shelter built around it, probes inside of it,
攝像頭  從外部泵入心臟血液
cameras, heart blood pumping from the outside,
毫無疑問
this is, without a doubt,
這是我們在節目中用過的
the most complex and sensitive experimental rig
最復雜也是最敏感的實驗設備
we have ever implemented on the show.
把湯湯放在干冰床上后...
With the Tauntaun laying atop his bed of dry ice...
好了
All right.
將其封箱
he is boxed in.
女士們  先生們  夜幕已降臨至霍斯
Ladies and gentlemen, night has fallen on Hoth.
溫度驟降  一切終于準備就緒
The temperature plummets and all is finally ready.
霍斯溫度  零下40攝氏度
我們已經達到最低溫度極限
So we have hit our lower temperature limit.
在幾百磅干冰
Between the several hundred pounds of dry ice
和冷庫非常寒冷的環境溫度下
and the very cold ambient temperature here in the freezer
我們一直恒定地保持著零下40攝氏度
we are maintaining a steady negative 40 degrees Celsius.
雖然沒有達到霍斯星的最冷的溫度
Now it's true that is not the coldest possible temperature on Hoth,
霍斯
地區  外層空間
直徑  7200公里
氣溫  -32℃~-61℃
但已經處于該范圍內
but it is smack in the middle of the butter zone,
我們對此很是滿意
and we are happy with that.
-好了  先生  是時候了  -開始
- All right, sir, it's time. - Off we go.
問題是盧克要在里面待多久
The question is, how long does Luke have in here?
漢說過這能在我挖好雪洞之前讓你保持體溫
Well, Han says this will keep you warm until I can get a shelter built.
時間零點  盧克核心溫度  35攝氏度
All right, time zero, Luke's core, 95.
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
37攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
在極惡劣的情況下
Now average time it will take a climber
一般一個登山者要花費
under very adverse conditions
兩到三個小時來搭建一個雪洞
to build a snow cave is between two and three hours.
-我搭過雪洞  知道嗎  -是嗎
- I've built a snow cave, you know.  - Yeah.
在山頂搭了個雪洞  然后過了一晚
Spent the night in one up on a mountain top.
鑒于漢是個能干的小伙兒  還拿著光劍
Given that Han is a capable fellow, he's got a lightsaber
因此我們設定盧克需要堅持兩個半小時
we are giving him two and a half hours
直到雪洞搭完
for Luke to survive long enough for the shelter to be built.
隨著時間的流逝
With the clock running...
我們現在要做的就是等待
All we got to do now is wait.
大家的目光都集中在溫度計上
it's all eyes on the gauges.
但其中一個溫度計搶先了一步
But one of them got a head start.
等等  我猜你們會說  什么
But wait, I can hear you saying, what?
人類體溫是37攝氏度
Human body temperature is 98.6.
為什么我們開始測試時
Why are we starting this test
盧克的體溫是35攝氏度
with Luke's body temperature at 95?
這是因為我們假設
Well it's because we are making the assumption that
他在之前已經損失了一些熱量
he's already suffered some heat loss.
受傷加上躺著等死
Injured and left for dead,
盧克已經有些輕度失溫
Luke is already mildly hypothermic.
好了  過了十分鐘
All right, ten minutes in.
來看看  34攝氏度  下降了一度
Let's see, 94, he's lost a degree.
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
34.5攝氏度
36.7攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
但他需要降至28攝氏度
But he has to hit 82 degrees,
才會達到死亡臨界點
the critical point of no return before he dies.
失溫水平
35.1至35攝氏度  顫抖
27.8至32.2攝氏度
肌肉僵硬  神志不清
低于27.8攝氏度
器官衰竭  死亡
他能堅持住嗎
Will he make it?
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
34.1攝氏度
35.6攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
過去一個小時了
It's one hour.
他的核心溫度還是34攝氏度
Still reading his core at 93.
心臟功率仍然是三百瓦
His heart is still pumping 300 watts.
血液正試圖為全身供暖
Blood trying to warm the outer extremities
驅散寒冷
of his body against the cold.
非常  非常緩慢地下降
Slowly, slowly failing.
我記得剛開始實驗時
I remember when we started this,
我認為這根本就是胡扯  肯定不可能
I thought total B.S., no way it's gonna work.
現在的問題是  漢能否在他死亡之前
The question is will Han get the ice cave built in time
及時把雪洞搭建好
before he reaches abject failure?
時間流逝  剛剛死去的潮濕又溫暖的湯湯
The time ticks away, and the wet and warm recently deceased Tauntaun
看起來正像漢所想的那樣起到了作用
appears to do exactly what Han intended.
因為兩個半小時后  雪洞建好了
Because in two and a half hours, the snow cave is built.
哥們  兩個半小時到了
Dude, two and a half hours is up.
我們去看看
Let's go check him out.
令人驚奇的是  熱力俠的新陳代謝
And amazingly, thermo-boy's human equivalent metabolism
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
33.3攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
才剛開始減緩
has only begun to cool down.
得到什么數據
What's the data say?
盧克躺進湯湯身體里時
Luke went into the Tauntaun,
輕度失溫  體溫是35攝氏度
he was mildly hypothermic, at 95 degrees
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
35攝氏度
37攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
但在過去的兩個小時里
and in the last two hours,
時間
盧克
湯湯
霍斯
33.3攝氏度
零下40攝氏度
體溫只降低到33攝氏度
he's dropped to only 92.
乍看起來  爬進動物尸體里
On the face of it, crawling into a dead animal carcass
不像是保暖的最佳方法
might not seem to be the best way to stay warm.
但實際上大部分哺乳動物含有75%的水分
But the thing is that most mammals are made up of about 75% water,
而水具有顯著的吸收和保存熱量的能力
and water has the phenomenal ability to absorb and retain heat.
因此如果你能找到一個大型動物的蓄熱體
So if you had access to the large thermal mass of a large animal,
想辦法鉆進去  就有可能保住性命
and could get inside it, it might just save your life.
這條流言有此可能
This myth is plausible.
雖然是虛構的  但是可行
However fictional, it's plausible.
太酷了
That's pretty cool.
有此可能
我們的旅行就此結束
And so, the journey ends.
正如牛頓幾乎說過的那樣
As Newton almost said,
力等于流言終結者乘以卓越
the force equals Mythbusters times awesome.
湯湯內臟
Tauntaun guts.
終結者們拉開帷幕
The team pulled back the curtain,
調查  探索  實驗
examined, explored and experimented.
他們驗證了最偉大的荒誕故事之一
They tested one of the greatest tall tales of all time...
你看起來太棒了
You look fantastic.
并使之成為現實
and made it a reality.
我們真的做到了
We totally made it!
來啊  你們這群帝國士兵
Bite me, empire!
全
新
一季
-準備好了嗎  -準備好了
- You're ready? - I'm ready.
簡直停不下來
It just didn't stop.
抓緊  加速  沖啊
Grabbing, speed, here we go!
開火
Fire.
這才是私釀酒
This is what moonshine is all about.
好了  我們準備登機
All right, we are ready to board.
你好嗎
How're you doing?
要鉆進他褲子里了
It's gonna go in his pants.
就是這樣
That's it.
這是我們做過的最難以置信的事
That was the most incredible thing we'd ever done.
你的結果也許有所不同
Your results may vary.
流言終結者